Guide to the Communications Workers of America, Local 1151 Records WAG.244
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Communications Workers of America, Local 1151 Records
1946-2001
1960-1989
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Communications Workers of America. Local 1151
Karl, Frank
Schaeffer, John
WAG.244
2.5 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, and 1 folder.
Communications Workers of America, Local 1151 represented AT&T and Bell System employees in the Albany, NY area. The Local had its historical roots in the founding period of the CWA, and a strong tradition of involvement in the CWA's national activities, based on the involvement of its long-time president Frank Karl. In addition to his service to the Local, Karl was a long-standing member of CWA's National Bargaining Committee. Not long before the donation of the records to the Archives, Local 1151 merged with the CWA's local in Syracuse, New York.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by former Communications Workers of America, Local 1151 President Frank Karl and Secretary-Treasurer John Schaeffer in April 2005. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2005.021, 2005.022 and NPA.2006.071.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Communications Workers of America, Local 1151 was chartered in 1951, to represent American Telephone & Telegraph's Long Lines (long distance) employees working in the Albany area. Local 1151 had its roots in the old Communications Workers of America (CWA) Division system, as Local 9 of Division No. 10.
Local 1151 was ably led by its long-time president, Francis (Frank) Karl. First elected in 1958, Karl would serve in this post for thrity-three years. In addition to his duties with the Local, President Karl performed service to the CWA international union by serving on the National Bargaining Committee, helping the union to negotiate six consecutive contracts.
Scope and Content Note
The Communications Workers of America, Local 1151 Records contains minutes, internal and outside correspondence, photographs, videos, and files on contracts, bonding information, financial statements, membership, and strikes.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically within each series.
The files are grouped into three series:
Missing Title
Minutes
Correspondence
Subject Files
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Records of the Communications Workers of America (WAG 124)
Records of the Communications Workers of America (WAG 124.1)
Records of Communications Workers of America, Local 1150 (WAG 59)
Records of Communications Workers of America, Local 1153 (WAG 132)
Records of Communications Workers of America, District 1 (WAG 117)
Papers of Frank Karl (WAG 192)
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
American Telephone and Telegraph Company -- Employees.; Labor unions -- Organizing -- United States.; Videocassettes.; Strikes and lockouts -- Telecommunication.; Telecommunication -- Employees -- United States.; Labor unions -- Elections -- United States.; Collective labor agreements -- Telecommunication.; Arbitration, Industrial.; Albany (N.Y.); Legal documents.; Company unions -- Telecommunication.; Reports.; Transcripts.; Labor unions -- Political activity -- United States.; Labor unions -- Telecommunication -- United States.; Labor unions -- Contract administration.; Labor unions -- Officials and employees.; Correspondence.; Financial records; Minutes (administrative records); Communications Workers of America. District 1; Communications Workers of America. Local 1151; Karl, Frank; American Telephone and Telegraph Company; Karl, Frank; Schaeffer, John
- Series I: Minutes, 1946-1994
  Scope and Content Note
  Series I: Minutes, consists of the minutes of Executive Board, General Membership, and Stewards meetings.
  - Minutes: Executive Committee, 1946-1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes: Executive Committee, 1963-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes: Executive Committee, 1979-1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes: Executive Committee, 1986-1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes: Executive Committee, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes: General Membership Meetings, 1963-1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes: General Membership Meetings, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes: Stewards Meetings, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes: Stewards Meetings, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes: Stewards Meetings, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1968-1999
  Series II: Correspondence, contains the internal correspondence of the Local, as well as correspondence exchanged with AT&T and other CWA organizations.
  - Correspondence: Bell Systems Units, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Internal, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Local, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Local, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Local, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Retirees, 1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series III: Subject Files, 1947-2001
  Series II: Subject Files includes contracts, grievances, photographs, five VHS tapes, and assorted files on the local's activities.
  - Absence Control: Policies and Grievances, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Affiliation, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Agency Shop, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - American Telephone and Telegraph (AT&T): Bargaining History, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Arbitration, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Audits, 1963-1978 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Bargaining, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bargaining, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bonding Information, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bonding Information, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bonding Information, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bylaws, 1959-1975 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Charter Change Proposals, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW), 1976 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Committee on Political Education (COPE), 1994 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Communications Workers of America (CWA) Publications, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Contract, 1963-1973 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Contract: Holidays, 1993-2001 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Contract Ratification, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Contracts: AT&T, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Contracts: Empire State Telephone Workers' Organization, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Contracts: Long Lines, 1955-1967 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Contracts: Long Lines, 1971-1983 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Convention Credentials: Karl, Francis (Frank), 1959-1979 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Conventions, 1960-1989 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Cost of Living Expenses (COLA), 1976 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - CWA-CIO Shop Stewards Convention, 1951 (Box OS007, Folder 1)
  - Defense Fund, 1963-1972 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Defense Fund, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Defense Fund, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Department of Labor, New York State, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Department of Labor, United States: Legal Notice-Violation of "No-Strike" Clause, Aug 7, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Dues Reports, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Dues and Membership Reports, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Dues Policy, 1992-1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Early Historical Materials, 1947-1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Elections, 1957-1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Election, Special: Secretary, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Federal Forms, 1959-1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Financial Statements, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Financial Statements, 1987, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Fiscal Reports, 1964-1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Founding Documents, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Grievance: DDD Operations-Lost-Time for Military Service, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Grievance: Smoking Policy, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Grievances, 1966-1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Grievances, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Installation Nite Event, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Installation of Officers, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Labor Law (Regulations, Forms, etc.), 1969-1974 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Labor Relations, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Local Headquarters Lease, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Long Lines Picnic Announcement, Jul 25, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Membership Lists, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Membership Reports, 1966-1973 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Member Resignations, 1968-1977 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Member Transfer, Appeal Against, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Memorandum of Understanding, 1968-1972 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Memorandum of Understanding: AT&T, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Memorandum of Understanding: Overtime, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Merger Discussions: CWA with American Postal Workers Union (APWU) and National Association of Letter Carriers (NALC), 1973 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Newsletter, Local, 1959-1996 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Nolan, Howard C.: Senate Campaign, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Payroll Information, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Personal Computers, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Photographs, circa 1965-1979 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Restructuring Union, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Retired Members Club, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Retired Members Council, 1989-1993 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Social Security Information, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Strike, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Strike, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Strike: Dues Rebate, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Supplemental Pension Plan, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Tax Forms, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Tri-Cities Council, 1962-1973 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Union Policies, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Videos (Box 3)
  - Wage Schedule, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Workplace of the Future, 1992-1997 (Box 2, Folder 45)